frugalnovice.com 2016-10-20

# Privacy Policy & Disclosure Statement – Frugal Novice

**Privacy Policy**

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at frugalnovice [at] gmail [dot] com.

At frugalnovice.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by frugalnovice.com and how it is used.

• Log Files  
Like many other Web sites, frugalnovice.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

• Cookies and Web Beacons  
frugalnovice.com does not use cookies.

• DoubleClick DART Cookie  
.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on frugalnovice.com.  
.:: Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to frugalnovice.com and other sites on the Internet.  
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ….  
Google Adsense and Burst Media

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on frugalnovice.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

frugalnovice.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. frugalnovice.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

**Disclosure Statement**

This policy is valid from 20 October 2011

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by me. For questions about this blog, please contact  Christi (frugalnovice {at} gmail {dot} com).

This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation.

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards. We believe in honesty of relationship, opinion and identity. The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space or post will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content.

The owner(s) of this blog is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner(s) of this blog receives compensation for our posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.  
To get your own policy, go to http://www.disclosurepolicy.org
